Now, let's summarize the time and space complexity of to the array and the operations.
If I create an empty array, then the time complexity to do this creation is of one.
But the space complexity is of our time.
See?
Please write them down, guys.
This this table, because it's very important and it summarizes all of operations and give you an example
or an idea what we are going to do.
And if you write a specific code that it is like near this or not, exactly all of our see, for example,
as basic complexity or all of one lifetime complexity, then you should know that your algorithm is
wrong or true.
So this is very important and it's summarized many operations.
So the time complexities of one, I'm just creating an empty array about the space complexity depends
on the row number and the column number.
OK.
So how many rows inside the array I'm making, like five.
And the column like six, so it is of five times six.
It's about row times come at the space because they will reserve like 30 and 30 boxes inside the memory.
Inserting a value in array, it will consume time, complexity of one and space, complexity of one
because I'm complexity for inserting and value just one because I am adding value and getting they use
it from the user input and inserting it into their array.
And the space complexity, I have created an empty I have reserved the memory and the space in memory
for that old and columns and just updating the memory with the values now traversing in a given array.
Traversing a given array means that we are looping through all the elements.
So time complexity, it is all of our key.
Because I am walking through, I am going through all the elements of rows and columns that I have.
Biospace complexities of one, because I'm just reading.
Accessing a given cell, it will give us one for time complexity and the space complex because accessing
and a space complexity is often.
I'm just reading from memory, but in time complexity.
It is all fun because I am directly accessing by specifying the index of the arrow and the index of
the column.
And this is the very important thing about the arrays when you need to access and search sorry access
or insert or traverse the arrays.
OK, but it's mainly when you need a fast accessing.
You need to use every when you search for a given value.
You are going to loop through all the elements so looping through all elements it will give us or result
in looping through all the rows and rows and rows and columns.
OK, so at this time, complexity of our RC and space complexity of one because I'm not doing anything
in the memory.
And deleting a given value, it's all of one because I'm specifying a specific index, and I am just
altering it by deleting a given value into the array I am talking about to the array deleting.
It's not time and space complexity of one the array.
OK.
Because deleting is different into the array is different from one the array.
So deleting any given array of two.
The array is all of one, and the space complexity is all of what I need from you to understand to think
about this table and write it down because you may encounter a question about it interview or that university.